Pavel Šťastný

Front end developer

**** 732106749

Vizovice, Czechia

My Website

in LinkedIn

Github



Profile

I'm someone who's always striving to improve, gain experience, and keep learning. I've got a curious mind, and I enjoy experimenting on my own. I'm particularly drawn to front-end technologies, which I'm actively specializing in. However, I'm also genuinely curious about backend. I'm good at picking up things fast and staying determined to reach my goals.

Professional Experience

Front-end developer, YunexTraffic s.r.o. □

- Development of web applications and React component library as a part of FE/UX team.

- Tech stack: React, Typescript, Redux, GitLab CI/CD, Jira, (MUI, Mapbox).

- Improved performance of multiple react components for low-end devices.
- Leading role in releases of UI library and other inner packages.
- Enhanced code quality across various legacy projects by implementing a robust linting tools, performing comprehensive refactoring and codebase linting.
- Improved UX of apps with thorough code reviews, constructive discussions, and effective merge requests.

Web Developer, Papirfly ☑

- Developement of web applications and various websites for clients.

- Tech stack: JavaScript/TypeScript, Angular, CSS (SASS), HTML, Gulp, Pug, Mapbox

- As the sole FE dev on the project, I created a SPA using vanilla JavaScript, utilizing class-based components, SCSS styles and REST API.

Software tester, *TwinSoft s.r.o* □

Freelance Engagements

- Manual and automated testing of a web application, including SQL database interaction. Enhanced the app's UX through valuable feedback.

- Demonstrated effective communication with clients, developers, and stakeholders.

11/2017 – 07/2021

07/2021 - 04/2022

Zlín, Czechia

05/2022 - present

Brno, Czechia

Brno, Czechia

2021 - 2023

UX/UI developer at Visitpro.eu (part-time, 2021/03 – 2022/12)

• Coding UI elements, UX consultation, and styling; Tech: SCSS, GIT, Blazor, Next. JS.

Front-end developer at Awincado.cz (part-time, 2023/04 – 2023/08)

• UI developement and enhancing UX; Tech: Remix, Tailwind, Docker.

Education

Master's Degree in Economics, Masaryk University ☑

I began my studies in Business Informatics and later completed my degree in Economics. This diverse background helps me to see and solve problems from different perspective.

2017 - 2020

Brno, Czechia

Pavel Šťastný 1 / 2

Skills	♂ La	inguages
React (Component patterns, clean code, performance optimization)	Czech	• • • •
Typescript (Advanced usage from the perspective of library author)	Native	
CSS (SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, CSS-in-JS, Styled components)	English • • • • • ■ B2/C1	
HTML and Javascript (Modern JS, semantic HTML = strong basics)		
Front-end libraries and tools (AgGrid, MUI, Redux, Svelte, NextJS, Remix, Storybook, Vite/Webpack/Rollup/Gulp, Cypress, Jest)	French A2	• • • • •

Courses & Certificates

Web Developement Courses, Freecodecamp ☑ 2020 – 2021 Front End Development Libraries; Responsive web design; JS Algorithms and Data Structures CS50, Harvard University ☑ 2021 Introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming.

Full Stack Open, University of Helsinki	2020
Deep Dive Into Modern Web Development (FE + BE)	

♣ Interests

Soccer Ho	omebrewing	Sport in general
,	ike to experiment and brew my own uff.	I like all kind of sports ie. voleyball, chess, tenis and gym.

Pavel Šťastný 2 / 2